Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1880-1939; 1880-1901; VI.
  - Letters from APN to Others, 1899-1939; 4.
    - MISSINGSchirmer, Gustave (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 656)
      Unspecified sending address. Photocopy of ALS letter. With previous letter.
    - Thompson, Vance (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 657)
      65 Central Park West. ALS.
    - MISSING Thorton [Oakley], April 26, 1939 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 658)
      136 East 67 St. New York, NY. ALS: two? Missing.
  - Letters to APN from others, 1880-1935; 5.
    - Boardman, Alice L, April 12, 19[19] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 659)
      199 Marlborough St., Boston. ALS, TL.
    - Charlton, Loudon, G, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 660)
      Cleveland. ALS.
    - Dickson, Elizabeth, [1880] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 661)
      236 Broad Street, Sewickley, PA. ALS: From Doris Nevin (EWN's daughter).
    - MISSING Douglas, Mary, October 31, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 662)
    - Ellert, Laurence B, March 7, 1935 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 663)
      New York. ALS: Typed letter, concerning the manuscript "Dolce far niente."
    - Hughes, Rupert, April 17, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 664)
      25, Porchester Square, Hyde Park. ALS.
    - Hughes, Rupert, August 16, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 665)
      London. ALS.
    - Murray, Dr. P.J., October 10, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 666)
      Summerlea. ALS.
    - Pope, J. William, April 21, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 667)
      Pittsburgh. ALS.
    - Pedralli, Giovanni, May 9, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 668)
      Venezia. ALS: In Italian.
    - Rogers, Winthrop, June 4, 1919 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 669)
      35 Union Square, New York. ALS.
    - Schirmer, Ernest, February 10, 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 670)
      New York. ALS: Copy of a typed letter sent to Schott & Co., includes personal message at the bottom.
    - Schirmer, Ernest, March 10, 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 671)
      New York. ALS: Typed letter.
    - Schirmer, Ernest, April 1, 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 672)
    - Thompson, Vance (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 673)
      Hotel Wolcott, Room 213. ALS.
    - Windeler, Laura, May 30, 1909 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 674)
      65 Bay State Rd. [Boston]. ALS, TL.
    - Euglar, Mary, November 5, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 675)
      New York City. ALS.
    - [Freeman], Mrs. W. H to Anne Nevin, April 29, 1916 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 676)
      [to] Anne Paul Nevin. ALS.
    - Cather, Willa to Nevin, Anne Paul, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 677)
      Handwritten, signed letter of sympathy. 7 pages.
  - Other Copies of Letters, 1885-1898; 6. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 678)
    Small note in with the Letters from family to EWN. All letters from 1885 except for the insert with 1889(?) and the family tree with 1898. All items are in the extract folder except for the family tree which is in Oversize Items.
    - Father, January 3, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item a)
    - Mother (extract), January 16, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item b)
    - Mother, March 5, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item c)
    - Mother, March 15, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item d)
    - Mother, March 22, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item e)
    - Mother, April 21, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item f)
    - Mother (extract), May 24, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item g)
    - Mother, June 7, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item h)
    - Mother, October 14, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item i)
    - Mother, October 28, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item j)
    - ?? (Unidentified family member), November 2, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item k)
    - Mother (extract), October 9, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item l)
    - Mother, November 23, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item m)
    - Mother, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item n)
      Unknown month
    - Mother, December 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item o)
      No Subnote Content
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1914-1937; 7.
    - MISSING Page, Walter H, February 28, 1914 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 679)
      To Page, Mr. TL: Copy of a letter to the Atlantic Monthly and concerns the authorship of the poem "The Rosary." Found in "Articles."
    - Shook, Jr., Willis to Elizabeth Dickson, March 14, 1937 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 680)
      To Elizabeth Dickson. ALS: Includes article: "Composer Nevin Spurned Girls of Sewickley."
- Photographs, 1862-1980; VII.
  The photographs are arranged in chronological order, with Nevin's life divided into seven periods. Three additional groups were added to this collection: After Nevin's death; Others; and Photos presented by the Dicksons. The dimensions of the photos are indicated. If a photo is framed, the frame itself is excluded from those measurements. If the photos are numbered, those numbers are provided in the scope and contents of the individual items.
  - Childhood in Sewickley, PA, 1862-1878; 1.
    - Ethelbert Nevin, A.
      - Ethelbert Nevin with his Nurse (Viney) age 1 year., 1864 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.08)
        1 photo; 10 x 6 cm. Gano studio, Pittsburgh. One year old. 00661.8
      - Ethelbert Nevin aged 2 years old, 1865 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.09)
        10 x 7 cm. 00661.1 Dabb's studio, Pittsburgh. Two years old. 2 copies
      - Ethelbert Nevin in Dresden, age 15, 1878 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.01)
        Hugo Thiele Photography, 31 Prager St., Dresden.
      - Ethelbert Nevin aged four years old, 1867 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.06)
        1 photo; 10 x 6 cm. Dabb's studio, Pittsburgh. Four years old. 00661.6
      - Ethelbert Nevin age five years old, 1868 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.04)
        1 photo; 10 x 6 cm. Dabb's studio, Pittsburgh. Five Years Old. 00661.4
      - Ethelbert Nevin age 6 years old, 1869 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.02)
        1 photo; 11 x 7 cm. Fassett studio, Chicago. Six years old.
      - Ethelbert Nevin with his older brother Hughes Nevin, 1871 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.2)
        1 photo; 10 x 5 cm. Framed tintype. Eight years old. Hughes Nevin is the older brother of E.W.N. Was missing, Found 5/16/05 BAN.
      - Ethelbert Nevin at the age of fourteen, 1877 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.03)
        1 photo; 11 x 7 cm. Robinson studio, Pittsburgh. Fourteen years old.
      - Ethelbert Nevin age fifteen years old, 1878 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.12)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Dabbs studio, Pittsburgh. Fifteen years old.
    - Other Photographs, B.
      - Sarah Nevin Henderson (Folder 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.14)
        1 photo; 10 x 6 cm. Great Grandaunt of E. W. N. 00661.14
      - Jane Cree Oliphant, Nevin's maternal grandmother (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.05)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Grandmother of E.W.N. 00661.05
      - Margaret Williams Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's paternal grandmother (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 679)
        1 photo; 35 x 27 cm. Grandmother of E.W.N. 00679
      - Elizabeth Duncan Oliphant Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's Mother (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.15)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Sperder studio, Pittsburgh. Mother of E. W. N. 00661.15
      - Elizabeth Oliphant Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's Mother, and Lily Nevin, Ethelbert's younger sister (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.11)
        1 photo; round shape, diameter 6 cm. Fassett studio, Chicago. Mother of E. W. N., with his younger sister. 00661.11
      - NEEDS ACCESSION # Robert P. Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's father (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 699)
        18 x 14 cm, framed.
      - Ethelbert Oliphant, the Uncle for whom Ethelbert Nevin was named (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.1)
        1 photo; 10 x 7 cm. Uncle of E. W. N. 00661.10
      - Ethelbert Nevin's nurse "Viney" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.07)
        1 photo; 10 x 6 cm. Nurse of E. W. N.
      - MISSING? Eames, Emma
        1 photo; 10 x 7 cm. In silver frame. Missing.
  - Student Days, 1878-1886; 2.
    - Ethelbert Nevin, 1882-1886; A.
      - Ethelbert Nevin aged 19 in Boston, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.09)
        1 photo; oval shape, 13 x 9 cm. Boston. Nineteen years old. Originally framed, now unframed.
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Elizabeth "Lizzie" Dickson (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.05)
        1 photo; 9 x 6 cm.
      - Ethelbert Nevin wearing the stickpin Anne Paul gave him when they became engaged, 1884 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.1)
        When first engaged, aged 22 years.
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Charles Scovel, July 1884 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.01)
        1 photo; 11 x 7 cm. Berlin. Twenty-two years old. Taken at the Home of Charles Mellor 00685.01
      - Ethelbert Nevin with C.V. Thompson, Isaac Craig, and C. W. Scovel, September 15, 1884 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.08)
        1 photo; 11 x 7 cm. Berlin. Twenty-two Years old
      - Ethelbert Nevin when a student in Berlin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.02)
        1 photo; 15 x 10 cm. 00685.02
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Charles Scovel in Berlin, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.06)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Germany, 1885. Twenty-three years old. 00685.06
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Elbert Baldwin, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.03)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Germany. Twenty-three years old. 00685.03
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Elbert Baldwin, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 691)
        1 photo: Daguerreotype; oval shape, 8 x 6 cm. Twenty-three years old. 00691.
      - Mother and Father Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin, Anne Paul Nevin, Nell Paul, and Elbert Baldwin on the way to Beyreuth, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.04)
        1 photo; 7 X 11 cm. On way to Beyreuth. Twenty-three years old. Anne Paul is the wife of EWN, Nell Paul is her sister. 00685.05, filed with 00685.04
      - Ethelbert Nevin with Mr. and Mrs. Jacob W, Anne Paul, and Elbert Baldwin, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 685.07)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. On way to Beyreuth. Twenty-three years old. 00685.07.
      - Clothilde von Finck at whose home Nevin lived while a student in Germany (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 692.01)
        14 x 9 cm. (00692.1) Berlin.
      - Clothilde von Finck in Berlin, July 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 692.02)
        Inscription in German on back of photo.
    - Other photographs, B.
      - Daniel Gregory Mason, a student of Ethlebert Nevin's (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 684)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. A student of E. W. N. 00684.
      - Studio photograph of Ronald Colman (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 668)
        1 photo; 13 x 10 cm. When a student in Berlin, [N.D.] [Not in R. C. M. master list]. 00668
  - Romance and Marriage, 1880-1888; 3.
    - Photographs of Anne Paul, 1880-1888; A.
      - Anne Paul Nevin in Pittsburgh while a student at Bishop Bowman's Institute, 1880 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.02)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Dabbs studio, Pittsburgh. When attending Bishop Bowman's Institute. 00670.02
      - Anne Paul Nevin in her bedroom playing the banjo at Edgewater, 1881 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.04)
        1 photo; 18 x 25 cm. In bedroom at Edgewater. Taken by Brandenburg. 00667.04
      - Anne Paul Nevin's Bedroom in Edgewater, Oakmont, 1881 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.09)
        00670.09
      - Anne Paul Nevin in Pittsburgh, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.05)
        2 photos; 17 x 11 cm. Dabbs studio, Pittsburgh. 00670.05
      - Anne Paul Nevin as a student in Berlin, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.06)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. In photo studio, Berlin. When a student in Germany. 00670.06
      - Anne Paul Nevin in London, 188-? (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.03)
        1 photo; oval shape, 11 x 8 cm; with border, 24 x 19 cm. Taken by Mendelsohn of London. 00670.03.
      - Ethelbert Nevin and Anne Paul Nevin on the front piazza at Edgewater taken by Ellen Paul, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 676.07)
        1 photo; 18 x 23 cm. On steps of Edgewater, Summer of 1887. Taken by Ellen Paul. Engaged. 00676.07.
      - Anne Paul Nevin in her wedding dress, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.01)
        1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Marshall studio, Boston. In wedding dress. 00670.01
    - Other Photographs, 1881-1893; B.
      - Music room of Ethelbert Nevin on Park St. in Boston, 1887-1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.1)
        1 photo; 21 x 10 cm. #7 Park Street, Boston. Music room on 4th floor. Taught here while living at Pinckney St. 00670.10
      - Anne Paul's bedroom at Edgewater, Oakmont (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.08)
        20 x 25 cm. Anne Paul Nevin's room at Edgewater. Lilly Langtry's picture in large frame on table.
      - St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Grant Street, where Ethelbert and Anne Paul Nevin were married, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 670.11)
        1 photo; 23 x 16 cm. Pittsburgh, [N.D.]. The church in which E.W.N. and A. P. N. were married. Print mounted on cardboard backing.
      - Music Room at Ouasi, Florida (Father Paul's residence), 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 675.04)
        18 cm x 27 cm. sketch with music of "Little Boy Blue" on back of photograph 00675.4
  - Quincy, Mass., 1888-1889; 4.
    - House where EWN and APN lived, 1888-1889, in Quincy, Mass (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.11)
      1 photo; 8 x 14 cm. Quincy, Dec. 1888. matted and mounted. Smaller Daguerreotype also available.
    - Anne Paul Nevin with son Paul Nevin, 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 675.02)
      1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Quincy, Mass. 00675.2
    - Elizabeth C. Adams, November 8, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 675.01)
      1 photo; 17 x 11 cm. Elm St., Quincy. Granddaughter of John Adams, former president of the USA. 00675.1
    - Adams House (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 675.03)
      1 photo; 16 x 22 cm. Quincy, [N.D.]. Includes E. C. Adams and her younger brother, Hull Adams. 00675.3, In "Oversize Items."
    - Tennis tournament, September 3, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 675.05)
      1 photo; 14 x 20 cm. Quincy. 00675.5
  - Boston, Mass., 1891-1893; 5.
    - Mrs. Gustave Schirmer, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.13)
      1 photo; 11 x 6 cm. Boston.
    - MISSING? Studio, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 135)
      1 photo; 11 x 6 cm. Boston. With previous photo.
    - Gustave Schirmer, August 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 135, Photos 698)
      1 photo; 11 x 15 cm. Boston. Framed. Sent to E. W. N. in Paris.
  - Years abroad in Florence and Venice, 1891-1896; 6.
    - Florence, 1891-1896; A.
      - Anne Paul Nevin and Children (Paul and Doris) in Florence, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 687.02)
        1 photo; 21 x 16 cm. Florence. matted. Newspaper print of photo 00687.2
      - Ethelbert Nevin, Richard Harding Davis and C. B. Davis, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 681)
        1 photo; 16 x 12 cm. Florence. Framed. 00681
      - Richard Harding Davis, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 687.01)
        1 photo; 14 x 10 cm. Given to E. W. N. in Florence, 189[6]. [R.C.M. master list indicates 1891]. Inscribed to Nevin from Harding. 00687.1
    - Venice, 1896; B.
      - Sibyl Sanderson, May 26, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 682)
        1 photo; 16 x 10 cm. [Venice]. Framed.
      - Marie Bremer, May 26, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 683)
        1 photo; 14 x 10 cm. [Venice]. Framed. 00683.
      - Home of Ethelbert Nevin in Venice, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.16)
        1 photo; 14 x 20 cm. Framed. Home of E. W. N. in Venice during the summer.
  - Sewickley, PA and New Haven, CT, 1898-1901; 7.
    - Sewickley, PA, 1898-1899; A.
      - Nevin Family in parlor at Vineacre (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 666.08)
        1 photo + 1 negative. 00666.8
      - Parlor at Vineacre (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 666.07)
        1 photo + 1 negative. 00666.7
      - House -- Queen Anne's Lodge (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.09)
        1 photo; 17 x 22 cm. Sewickley, PA. Inscribed: Workshop of Ethelbert Nevin 1899-1900. Sewickley, PA. 00662.9
      - Vineacre exterior in Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.17)
        2 prints, 25 x 20 cm. 00661.17 + 2 negatives
      - Entrance to Vineacre, Nevin's home in Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.18)
        1 photo and negative.
      - Entrance to Vineacre, birthplace of Ethelbert Nevin in Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 661.19)
        1 photo. Possible duplicate of 00661.18
      - Studio in Queen Anne's Lodge, Ethelbert Nevin at piano (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.1)
        1 framed photo + 1 negative; -- cm. Sewickley, [N.D.] 00662.10
      - Robert P. Nevin in the library at Vineacre (Nevin's father) (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 699)
        1 photo FRAMED; 12 x 16 cm. Sewickley, [N.D.]. Father Nevin in library at Vineacre. Framed.
      - Robert P. Nevin (Ethelbert Nevin's Father) on the porch at Vineacre in Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.08)
        1 photo; 15 x 20 cm + 1 negative. Sewickley, [N.D.] Father Nevin on porch at Vineacre. 00662.08
      - Ethelbert Nevin with his "Little Choir" at Vineacre in Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.07)
        1 photo; 12 x 17 cm. + 1 negative. Sewickley, [N.D.]. With EWN at piano and the girls in the choir standing around. Accompanied by a note identifying the name of each girl: Caroline, Jean, Doris Key; Margaret Slack, Annie Reed, Doris Nevin 00662.7
      - Ethelbert Nevin at Edgeworth with with John Philip Sousa, Adolph Foerster, Eugene Heffey, Sousa's manager, and Anne Paul Nevin, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.01)
        10 x 12 cm. and 22 x 16 cm. 2 prints, one blown up. Edgeworth, Sewickley, 1899. Gift of Mrs. Emma Raab of Johnstown, PA. Accompanied by Mrs. Raab's calling card. 00662.01
      - Ethelbert Nevin at Vineacre, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.02)
        1 photo; 10 x 12 cm. with border, 13 X 9 cm. without border. Vineacre, Sewickley. Inscribed: a few measures of "The home I spent with thee" dear heart. To Anne from Bert, 1898. 00662.2
      - Clara Dickson, boyhood friend of Ethelbert Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 666.04)
        1 photo; 9 x 14 cm. Sewickley, [N.D.]. with 00666.4
      - View from the terrace at Arcady (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 666.05)
        Postcard 00666.5
      - Anne Paul Nevin with Children in Sewickley (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.03)
        Sewickley.
      - Anne Paul Nevin in New York, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.05)
        1 photo + 1 negative; 17 x 11 cm. and 15 x 11 cm. [Sewickley]. In Paris dress. 00662.5
    - New Haven, CT, B.
      - House in which Ethelbert Nevin died on February 17, 1901 in New Haven, CT. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.04)
        1 photo; 10 x 11. New Haven, [N.D.]. 00662.4
      - Doris Nevin (daughter of Ethelbert Nevin) dressed as Little Bo Peep in New Haven, CT (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 662.06)
        1 photo; 23 x 14 cm. Mounted. New Haven, [N.D.]. 00662.6
  - After Nevin's Death in 1901, 8.
    - Anne Paul Nevin photo by Brandenburg (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.04)
      1 photo; 26 x 21 cm. [N.D.]. Taken by Brandenburg.
    - Anne Paul Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.06)
      1 photo; 36 x 28 cm. with border, 23 x 14 cm. without border. [N.D.] 00677.6
    - Anne Paul Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.05)
      1 photo; 23 x 18 cm. without border. [N.D.]. 00677.5, with oversize items.
    - Anne Paul Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.03)
      1 photo; 36 x 25 cm. [N.D.]. 00677.3, with oversize items.
    - Anne Paul Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.08)
      1 photo; 36 x 27 cm. with border, 24 x 18 cm. without border. [N.D.]. 00677.8, with oversize items.
    - Anne Paul Nevin photographed by Maurice Goldberg (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.07)
    - Anne Paul Nevin with daughter Doris (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.02)
      1 photo; 36 x 27 cm. with border, 23 x 18 cm. without border. [N.D.]. 00677.2
    - Anne Paul Nevin with daughter Doris looking at each other (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 677.01)
      1 photo; 36 x 27 cm. with border, 23 x 18 cm. without border. 00677.1, with oversize items.
    - Nevin collection exhibit at Musical Americana in State Museum (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 678.01)
      20 x 26 cm. + [1] sheet of introductory leaflet to the exhibition; 26 cm. Other collections in the exhibit include the works of Stephen Foster, Charles Cadman, and Henry Burleigh. 00678.1
    - Nevin collection exhibit at Musical Americana in State Museum (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 678.02)
    - Closeup of Nevin's gravestone at Arcady (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 688.02)
      18 x 13 cm (close up)
    - Ethelbert Nevin's grave in Sewickley cemetery (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 688.04)
      Ethelbert Nevin's grave in Sewickley. Notes on back of photo note that his grave was disintered and his remains removed to Maine after Anne Paul Nevin became frustrated that Sewickley failed to commemorate her husband.
    - Ethelbert Nevin's grave at Arcady, from side (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 688.03)
    - Ethelbert Nevin's Grave at Arcady, from foot (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 688.01)
    - Pictures of the Cast of Ethelbert Nevin's right hand taken after death, right side (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 10962.01)
      1 front view, 16 x 19 cm. with border, 10 x 13 cm. without border; 10962.1,
    - Pictures of the Cast of Ethelbert Nevin's right hand taken after death, front view (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 10962.02)
    - Pictures of the Cast of Ethelbert Nevin's right hand taken after death, left side (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 10962.03)
    - Doris Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's daughter, visiting the University of Pittsburgh, November 21, 1951 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 10694)
    - Doris Nevin, Ethelbert Nevin's daughter, visiting the University of Pittsburgh, November 21, 1951 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 695)
  - Others, 1886-1980; 9.
    - Ethelbert Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 10963)
      Framed photo autographed by Anne Paul Nevin to Frederick Shaefer with Ethelbert Nevin's signature inserted.
    - Anne Paul Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 694)
      1 photo; oval shape, 9 x 8 cm. Framed. 00694.
    - Anne Paul Nevin, 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 667)
      1 photo; oval shape, 13 x 9 cm. Taken by Mendelsohn of London. Photograph before which E.W.N. did all his composing. Called "The Madonna." Framed copy in elaborate wooden frame is missing.
    - Ethelbert Nevin at His Piano (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 663)
      1 photo; 17 x 23 cm. + 1 negative. In presentation folder E.W.N. at the piano in his studio. With oversized items.
    - Ethelbert Nevin at his desk at Queen Anne's Lodge, Vineacre, Sewickley, PA (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 1, Photos 690)
      1 photo; 18 x 22 cm. Sewickley, [N.D.] E.W.N. at desk where he did all his composing while living at "Queen Anne's Lodge" in Edgeworth, across from old family house Vineacre. Given to University of Pittsburgh by A. P. N. Framed. 00690.